Guide to the Evelyn Hardy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Evelyn Hardy papers
1950-1974
YCAL MSS 404
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(1 box)
Correspondence with various individuals and drafts of poems by Hardy. The bulk of the correspondence is with Alyse Gregory. The papers span 1950-1974.
Hardy, Evelyn, 1902-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Evelyn Hardy, 1981.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Evelyn Hardy
Evelyn Hardy was born on February 13, 1902 Gregory, Alyse (married)- many letters are about her after her death. letters to Evelyn Hardy after Alyse Gregory's death and relating to Evelyn Hardy's article on her life and character.
Scope and Contents
The Evelyn Hardy Papers contains correspondence with various individuals and drafts of poems by Hardy. The bulk of the correspondence is with Alyse Gregory. The papers span 1950-1974.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Poets -- 20th Century; Gregory, Alyse, 1884-1967; Hardy, Evelyn, 1902-
- Correspondence
  - Anderson, Redwood, 1950 January 15 (Box 1)
  - Annand, Rupert, 1953 March 20 (Box 1)
  - De Lima, Agnes, 1968 May 12 (Box 1)
  - Gregory, Alyse, 1950-1967, undated; 7 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes "Alyse Gregory" typescript drafts by Hardy,
  - Lima, Ade, 1968 January 22 (Box 1)
  - Manning, Rosemary, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Parkes, Alan, 1967-1968, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Powys, John Cowper, 1950-1951, 1964 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence with Donald Wing regarding these letters
  - Scott-Maxwell, Florida, 1968-1972, undated (Box 1)
  - Unidentified correspondents, 1967, 1974 (Box 1)
    Letter to "Michaela" from Father Brocard
- Writings
  - Typescript drafts of poems, undated (Box 1)
- Empty envelopes (Box 1)